chipmark.com 2013-10-28

# Chipmark - Privacy

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. Chipmark agrees to notify you of: 

  * What personally identifiable information of yours is collected by Chipmark.
  * The organization collecting the information. 
  * How the information is used.
  * With whom the information may be shared.
  * The choices available regarding the collection, use and distribution of information.
  * The security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Chipmark's control.
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

The privacy practices of this statement apply to our services available under the domain and sub-domains of www.chipmark.com (the "Site"). By visiting this website, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree, please do not use or access our Site. 

This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect from you as part of the normal operation of our services and what may happen to that information. Although this policy may seem long, we have prepared a detailed policy because we believe you should know as much as possible about Chipmark's practices so that you can make informed decisions. 

By accepting the Privacy Policy and the User Agreement in registration, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your anonymous information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Chipmark will never release your personal information to anyone for any reason. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the Chipmark User Agreement. This Privacy Policy is effective upon acceptance in registration for new registering users, and is otherwise effective on October 31st, 2004 for all users. The previous amendment to this Privacy Policy was effective for all users on October 31st, 2004. 

Information collected online is usually defined as being either anonymous or personally identifiable. 

Anonymous Information refers to data that cannot be tied back to a specific individual. For example, Chipmark collects some information each time a visitor comes to Chipmark's site, so we can improve the overall quality of the visitor's online experience. Chipmark collects the visitor's IP address (i.e., whether the user is logged on from ibm.com or aol.com), referral data (i.e., the Internet address of the last Web page visited by a user before clicking over to the Chipmark site), and browser and platform type (e.g., a Netscape browser on a Macintosh platform). You do not have to register with Chipmark before we can collect this anonymous information. Chipmark's collection of bookmark information (e.g. url, name, description, hit count, etc.) is also considered anonymous information. 

Personally Identifiable Information refers to data that tells us specifically who you are, such as your name and postal address, which may be collected in addition to the anonymous data described in the above paragraph. 

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a website's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. 

Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. 

You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.) 

If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use Chipmark products or services that require you to "sign in," and you may not be able to take full advantage of all offerings. However, many Chipmark products and services do not require that you accept cookies. 

Chipmark uses its own cookies in order to:  
Maintain your login information if you select the auto-login feature. 

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the Chipmark website. On some pages, you can register for our Web bookmarks service. The types of personal information collected at these pages are:   
Email address  
A valid e-mail address is required at resistration for the purpose of retrieving your password should you forget it. On some pages, you can submit Web bookmark information. Under this circumstance, no personal information is collected. 

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and to share with researchers. For example, we may tell a researcher that X number of individuals visited a certain website, or that Y number of users filled out our registration form, but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals. 

We use your email address provided during registration only to contact you about important information related to Chipmark or to send you a lost password. Currently we don't disseminate information by email. Should we ever decide to do this you will have the option to receive emails or decline them. 

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. 

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. 

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13. 

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

You may not use the "Email This Item to a Friend" service or other email services that we offer to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our User Agreement. We do not permanently store email messages or the email addresses sent from these tools. 

If you send and email using the Email This Item to a Friend service to an email address that is not registered in our community, we do not use that email address for any purpose other than to send your email. We do not rent or sell these email addresses. 

In order to facilitate Web browsing, Chipmark allows you limited access to other users' Web bookmark information. As a member, you do not have access to other user's personal information. 

By entering into our User Agreement, you agree that, with respect to other users' anonymous information that you obtain through the Site, Chipmark hereby grants to you a license to use such information only for: (a)Web browsing. 

You are responsible for all actions taken with your user id and password. Therefore, we do not recommend that you disclose your Chipmark password to any third parties. If you choose to share your user id and password or your personal information with third parties, you are responsible for all actions taken with your account. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password in the account section of your members area. 

You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by visiting the account area of your member section . We use this procedure to better safeguard your information. 

You can correct errors in your personally identifiable information by visiting the account section of your members area. 

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. 

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on the Site. All amended terms shall automatically be effective 30 days after they are initially posted on the Site. In addition, we will notify you by email if you have supplied an email address during registration and have not opted out of our informational mailing list. 

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please send us an email at [chipmark@live.com](mailto:chipmark@live.com).
